<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>infrastructure on ASAP Discovery Consortium</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/tags/infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in infrastructure on ASAP Discovery Consortium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asapdiscovery.org/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Torsion Meeting Summary (May 14, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/science/updates/torsion-meeting-2019-05-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/science/updates/torsion-meeting-2019-05-14/</guid><description>TorsionDrive: Y. Qiu updated TorsionDrive with visualization and more documentation. He is planning to add functionality to TorsionDrive to store gradients, which are currently computed, but not recorded. D. Smith suggested having a schema defined for TorsionDrive jobs for future use, to facilitate using it in larger project infrastructure.
Torsion/Valence Fitting: There was discussion of when fitting with ForceBalance might start. L.-P. Wang estimated that, provided with our first round of finished QC calculations, ForceBalance might take about a day to run before providing an optimized set of parameters.</description></item><item><title>Torsion Meeting Summary (Mar 5, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/science/updates/torsion-meeting-2019-03-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/science/updates/torsion-meeting-2019-03-05/</guid><description>TorsionDrive: Y. Qiu started working on TorsionDrive and was unable to replicate D. Smith&amp;rsquo;s previously reported issue with 120 degree scan intervals. D. Smith confirmed that he was also unable to replicate and he suspects it might have been a version issue.
QCFractal: Stable version of QCFractal is out and should be installed through pip or conda - always conda install qcportal -c conda-forge. QCPortal might throw an error if an older version of QCFractal is used.</description></item></channel></rss>