<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AI-driven Structure-enabled Antiviral Platform (ASAP) on ASAP Discovery Consortium</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/</link><description>Recent content in AI-driven Structure-enabled Antiviral Platform (ASAP) on ASAP Discovery Consortium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asapdiscovery.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benchmark: OpenFF performance on small molecule energies and geometries</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/benchmark_small_molecules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/benchmark_small_molecules/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Initiative, focusing on open tools and science to improve accuracy of molecular modeling, has now been up and running for approximately 18 months. Recent highlights have included the release of a series of updates to Parsley, a small molecule force field for biomolecular simulation, which is now at version OpenFF-1.2.0. Parsley was iteratively optimized to improve agreement with quantum chemical geometries, energetics, and vibrational frequencies.
Here, we provide a preliminary benchmark assessment of several small molecule force fields (FF) compared to quantum mechanical (QM) results regarding gas phase energies and geometries of a set of molecule conformers.</description></item><item><title>Lee-Ping Wang stepping down from a leadership role</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/lpw-stepdown/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/lpw-stepdown/</guid><description>From August 1, the Open Force Field Initiative will undergo a change in the leadership team, as Lee-Ping Wang has decided to step down from his role as an OpenFF primary investigator. This not a farewell, but a change of roles and Dr. Wang will remain actively involved in OpenFF research efforts as a co-investigator. The Open Force Field Initiative owes a great deal of its success to the work done by Dr.</description></item><item><title>Jun 17, 2020 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-06-17-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-06-17-minutes/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on June 17, 2020. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Change in OpenFF leadership Lee-Ping Wang announced that he will step down from the leadership role in OpenFF on July 15, 2020. This decision is primarily driven by a desire to spend more time on research and exploration of new scientific decision and to reduce his involvement in the management duties of the Initiative.</description></item><item><title>May 20, 2020 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-05-20-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-05-20-minutes/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on May 20, 2020. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Infrastructure update J. Wagner gave an infrastructure update based on his talk presented during the recent virtual Third Open Force Field Workshop on May 4-5, 2020. Suggestions for QCArchive to incorporate some quality control information about molecular geometries and potential connectivity changes. At the moment, OpenFF is trying to generate SMILES before and after calculations.</description></item><item><title>Open Force Field Consortium Virtual Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/may-2020-virtual-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/may-2020-virtual-meeting/</guid><description>We are hosting the Third Open Force Field Consortium Workshop, this time in the online world of Zoom, on May 4-5, 2020. This virtual meeting is replacing the planned in-person gathering in Boston. We decided to slightly experiment with the workshop format by making most of the content available before the meeting for asynchronous consumption. Namely, all talks will be pre-recorded and the meeting time will be focused on discussions around those talks and future planning.</description></item><item><title>Apr 15, 2020 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-04-15-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-04-15-minutes/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on April 15, 2020. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Brief Update D. Mobley provided a brief progress update since the last meeting. S. Boothroyd is working on a feasibility study for optimal combinations of physical properties for fitting nonbonded parameters. openff-1.2.0 release will contain an improved QM training set with a more systematic approach to molecule selection, while Sage will include the LJ refit based on the feasibility study.</description></item><item><title>Open Force Field Initiative receives NIH funding</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/openff-nih-funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/openff-nih-funding/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that the NIH Institute of General Medical Sciences has funded our Focused Technology Research &amp;amp; Development R01 proposal, enabling the Open Force Field Initiative to partner with the biopolymer force field community and extend our infrastructure and force fields to also cover biopolymers. This is a collaborative NIH grant, with $380K direct costs/year for four years shared over the five main academic sites (University of Colorado Boulder, Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, University of California, Irvine, University of California, San Diego, and University of California, Davis), and includes significant funded collaborations with the MolSSI QCArchive and the AMBER community (via David Cerutti at Rutgers).</description></item><item><title>Mar 19, 2020 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-03-18-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-03-18-minutes/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on March 18, 2020. The minutes are summarized as follows:
The meeting has been cancelled due to workplace disruptions caused by the COVID19 outbreak. The in-person meeting has been postponed for November 9-10, while the meeting in May will be virtual. Katharina Meier and Thomas Fox have been confirmed as the industry representatives on the Governing Board for the next 6 months. The election period and voting protocol will be discussed during the next meeting.</description></item><item><title>The Third Open Force Field Consortium Workshop</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/may2020-meeting-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/may2020-meeting-announcement/</guid><description>The in-person meeting in Boston has been cancelled due to COVID-19 outbreak. Please save the dates (May 4-5, 2020) for the remote meeting. More details coming up soon. If you want to join the remote meeting, please fill out the form below. We are excited to announce the Third Open Force Field Consortium Workshop on May 4-5, 2020! This time we meet in Cambridge, MA and the venue has been generously provided by Pfizer, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Feb 19, 2020 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-02-19-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-02-19-minutes/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on February 19, 2020. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Next FF release plans I. Craig (BASF) reported some issues with nitrogen parameters in tetrazoles, and H. Jang has updated a couple of parameters in the recently released minor release - openff-1.1. D. Mobley presented some benchmarking results from V. Lim’s study of conformer energies and geometries. For geometry comparison, RMSD and torsion fingerprinting deviation (TFD) were used as similarity measures.</description></item><item><title>Jan 15, 2020 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-01-15-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2020-01-15-minutes/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on January 15, 2020. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – Jan 19, 2020 Protein-ligand benchmarking D. Hahn gave an update on his progress with protein-ligand benchmarking of Parsley &amp;ndash; he is currently working on developing a repository for storing and presenting data used for protein-ligand benchmarking studies, which stores only primary data reported in cited publications (derived data, for example dG, is converted on the fly from IC50, Kd, etc) D.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Andreas Krämer: Automated Optimization Approaches for the CHARMM Lipid Force Field (Dec 17, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-kraemer-dec2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-kraemer-dec2019/</guid><description>Andreas Krämer (NIH) will give a talk about development of an automated optimization approach to improve the CHARMM36 lipid force field using pair-specific LJ parameters. Join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Dec 17 at 2 pm (ET), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** The [CHARMM36 (C36) lipid force field](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2922408/) is well-validated for many properties of monolayers and bilayers and has been cited in over 2000 studies of membrane simulations.</description></item><item><title>Nov 19, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-11-19-minuted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-11-19-minuted/</guid><description>The [Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board] met on November 19, 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – Nov 19, 2019 Personnel update Y. Qiu and D. Slochower have left their positions at UC Davis and UC San Diego, respectively S. Boothroyd moved from the Chodera lab at MKSCC, New York to the Shirts lab at CU Boulder, Colorado OpenFF is hiring more personnel, primarily software scientists OFF toolkit update Version 0.</description></item><item><title>Oct 16, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-10-16-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-10-16-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board had an in-person meeting during the Consortium workshop in San Diego (Aug 30-31, 2091), discussing research questions of interest and potential future directions for the Open Force Field Initiative. This and other discussions held during the meeting made a basis for the roadmap for Year 2. This was the joint August/September meeting.
The minutes from the meeting held on Oct 16, 2019 are summarized as follows:</description></item><item><title>The Open Force Field 1.0 small molecule force field, our first optimized force field (codename "Parsley")</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-openforcefield-1.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-openforcefield-1.0/</guid><description>We’re delighted to announce the release of &amp;ldquo;Parsley&amp;rdquo;, the Open Force Field 1.0 small molecule force field&amp;mdash;the first in a series of iteratively-improved small molecule force fields for biomolecular simulation funded in part by the Open Force Field Consortium. This is the first optimized force field to use the SMIRNOFF force field specification for atom type-free direct chemical perception, and provides substantially improved valence (bond, angle, and torsion) parameters relative to its predecessor, the AMBER-lineage SMIRNOFF99Frosst.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Yuanqing Wang: Graph Nets for partial charge prediction (Oct 14, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-wang-oct2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-wang-oct2019/</guid><description>Yuanqing Wang(MSKCC) will give a talk about using Graph Nets for fast prediction of atomic partial charges. The preprint is available on here. Join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Oct 14 at 1 pm (EDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** Here we show that Graph Nets — a set of update and aggregate functions that operate on molecular topologies and propagate information thereon — are capable of predicting properties of atoms and molecules which would otherwise require expensive Quantum Mechanics (QM) calculations.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Falk Hoffmann: Using NMR relaxation data to improve the dynamics of methyl groups in AMBER and CHARMM force fields (Sep 20, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-hoffman-sep2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-hoffman-sep2019/</guid><description>Falk Hoffmann from Lars Schaefer&amp;rsquo;s group at Ruhr University Bochum, will present his work on improving torsional barriers associated with methyl group rotations in amino acid side-chains in AMBER and CHARMM force fields by using NMR relaxation rates. This study is available as a preprint on ChemrXiv. Join this seminar via Zoom in real time on Sep 20 at 11 am (EDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Chuan Tian: ff19SB - Amino acid specific protein backbone parameters trained against quantum mechanics energies in solution (Sep 12, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-tian-sep2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-tian-sep2019/</guid><description>Chuan Tian from the Simmerling lab will visit the Chodera lab at MSKCC and give a talk about the latest Amber force field - ff19SB. Join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Sep 12 at 1 pm (EDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations have become increasingly popular in studying the motions and functions of biomolecules. The accuracy of the simulation, however, is highly determined by the classical force field (FF), a set of functions with adjustable parameters to compute the potential energy from atomic positions.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Pankaj R. Daga: Data Curation - The Forgotten Practice in The Era of AI (Sep 13, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-daga-sep2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-daga-sep2019/</guid><description>Pankaj R. Daga from Simulation-Plus will visit the Mobley group at UC Irvine and give his CADD GRC talk about all the hazards that can appear in trying to automate mining of chemical and chemistry-related databases. You can join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Sep 13 at 11 am (PDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** Availability of large databases of chemical structures along with experimental data provides a great opportunity to build predictive and robust QSAR/QSPR models for application in various fields.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Vytautas Gapsys: Benchmarking binding free energy calculations for protein-ligand systems (Aug 21, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-gapsys-aug2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-gapsys-aug2019/</guid><description>Vytautas Gapsys (de Groot lab) will be hosted by the Mobley lab at UC Irvine, where he will present his work on calculations of relative ligand-protein affinities using Gromacs+pmx approach. His talk will also cover a free energy scan based on the non-equilibrium protocol covering ~500 ligand modifications across 13 protein-ligand systems, and provide a comparison of the obtained results to FEP+ calculations. The talk will be followed by a few slides to start discussion about absolute free energies and equilibrium vs.</description></item><item><title>The Open Force Field Toolkit 0.5.0, adding GBSA support</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/openforcefield-toolkit-0.5-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/openforcefield-toolkit-0.5-release/</guid><description>This release adds support for the GBSA tag in the SMIRNOFF specification. Currently, the HCT, OBC1, and OBC2 models (corresponding to AMBER keywords igb=1, 2, and 5, respectively) are supported, with the OBC2 implementation being the most flexible. Unfortunately, systems produced using these keywords are not yet transferable to other simulation packages via ParmEd, so users are restricted to using OpenMM to simulate systems with GBSA.
OFFXML files containing GBSA parameter definitions are available, and can be loaded in addition to existing parameter sets, for example, with the command:</description></item><item><title>Jul 17, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-07-17-minutes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-07-17-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on July 17, 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – July 17, 2019 The Advisory Board format was slightly changed on this occasion - the report about the latest development was sent before the meeting to leave more time for questions and discussions. We will test this new format during the next few meetings. Feedback and comments are welcome!</description></item><item><title>Aug 2019 Open Force Field Consortium Workshop</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/aug-2019-meeting-announcement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/aug-2019-meeting-announcement/</guid><description>We are hosting the Second Open Force Field Consortium Workshop in La Jolla, CA on August 30-31, 2019. The first two days of the workshop will focus on the progress update and future planning of OpenFF efforts in Year 2. The third day (Sep 1) is reserved for OpenFF team discussions, but open to interested Industry Partners. The event will be again hosted at UCSD campus, but please note that the venue has been relocated from Jacobs Medical Center used in January to the Skaggs School of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences building.</description></item><item><title>Jun 13, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-06-13-minutes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-06-13-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 13 June, 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – June 13, 2019 First optimized force field (D. Mobley):
Aiming to have the first force field released by Sept 1 and evaluations performed by Oct 1. Specific discussion about it takes place in #release-1 channel on Slack.
Types: The same typing tree as smirnoff99Frosst will be used, but the differentiable parameters in (a subset of) torsion, valence, and Lennard-Jones parameters will be optimized;</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Chaya Stern: Fragmenting molecules for QC torsion drives (Jun 4, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-torsions-chaya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-torsions-chaya/</guid><description>You can watch this webinar on YouTube and access slides on Zenodo.
Chaya Stern (Chodera lab) will give a webinar on Jun 4 at 11 am (EDT) under title “Fragmenting molecules for QC torsion drives”, based on her talk presented at the ACS Orlando conference (Mar 31 - Apr 4, 2019). Join the webinar in real time via Zoom link (https://meetmsk.zoom.us/j/987691623) or for those who can’t make it, Chaya’s talk will be recorded and shared on the website.</description></item><item><title>May 15, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-05-15-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-05-15-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 15 May, 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – May 15, 2019 Overview of the roadmap for the remaining time of Year 1 and the accomplishments made so far (J. Chodera).
Torsions update (L.-P. Wang):
The selected set of molecules for initial torsion scanning contains 486 small and chemically diverse molecules provided by Roche (less than 30 heavy atoms)- “Roche set”- more fragments will be added to this set in the future;</description></item><item><title>April 17, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-04-17-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-04-17-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 17 April 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – 17 April 2019 K. Condic-Jurkic to take over future agenda planning with input from D. Kuhn, I. Craig, A. Narayanan Release update by Jeff Wagner: 0.2.1 bugfix release on the 12th after initial 0.2.0 release on 8th Version numbers indicate API is still in flux, there may be function call changes, etc.</description></item><item><title>The 0.2.0 Toolkit release, now with RDKit support!</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/openforcefield-toolkit-0.2-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/openforcefield-toolkit-0.2-release/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the public release of the Open Force Field toolkit version 0.2.0! Most notably, this release adds the ability to assign SMIRNOFF parameters and AM1-BCC charges with a completely open-source backend, adding support for the RDKit and AmberTools via a new ToolkitWrapper infrastructure that can be extended in the future to support additional cheminformatics toolkits. The OpenEye Toolkit will continue to be supported, as well as used internally our parameter-fitting pipelines in the short term.</description></item><item><title>March 20, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-03-20-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-03-20-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 20 March, 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – March 20, 2019 Status Updates: OFFI NIH proposal submitted and available publicly Hiring update: Karmen Condic-Jurkic starts April 1 as half-time scientific coordinator/project manager Interviews ongoing for bespoke torsion fitting and potentially electrostatics role Open Force Field Toolkit update: Alpha release slated for April 2 Will contain RDKit backend support in abstracted cheminformatics structure (allowing future support for alternative cheminformatics packages to be easily added) Supposed to give same results regardless of RDKit or OpenEye (tested with ~2k molecules from eMolecules to have same energies, forces, and force terms) Differences in aromaticity models could result in some differences in corner cases We are adding a “paranoid mode” so we can detect differences between toolkits that arise when building force fields SDF with standardized tags will be the supported method for importing molecules with custom charges OpenEye and RDKit on-board with standardized tags for charges There may have been minor changes to XML forcefield format since the January preview release Changes are summarized here OFFI hope is to have weekly/biweekly bugfix or feature releases and conda package updates Partners and users are directed to use the Github issue tracker to report issues or problems Technical questions – Desmond support How is Desmond currently used by Partners?</description></item><item><title>Open Force Field Initiative applies for NIH funding</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/seeking-nih-funding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/seeking-nih-funding/</guid><description>The ultimate goal of the Open Force Field Initiative is to produce modern, high-quality tools for building better force fields, and to apply these tools to produce consistently more accurate generations of biomolecular force fields that are incredibly easy to use in a variety of molecular simulation packages.
Anyone who has tried simulating complex, heterogeneous systems involving small molecules, proteins, lipids, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, post-translational modifications, cofactors, and covalent ligands (or any subset of these!</description></item><item><title>February 20, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-02-20-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-02-20-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 20 February, 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – February 20, 2019 Next release of toolkit currently being tested and finished Workflow documentation Next item on to-do list Call for additional desired workflows to be posted in #documentation channel Industry compound additions to parameterization sets Starting small – current focus is finding parameters in need of optimization by looking for discrepancies between current forcefields when minimizing structures Industry partners should identify particularly high priority chemical space for initial parameterization Compounds/fragments to be sent via Slack or GitHub BI has SureChembl dump and scripts that may be able to be shared.</description></item><item><title>January 23, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-23-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-23-minutes/</guid><description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 23 Jan 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – January 23, 2019 RDKit Integration Key infrastructure seems to be working Currently implementing testing to make sure energies/parameters are same between RDKit and OpenEye toolkit backends Documentation being worked on Limited to SDF file format initially RDKit support being added initially for OpenFF toolkit, not for other packages being used internally for parameter development Bespoke torsion parameterization tool will be able to use RDKit or other wholly open-source backend Workflows Workflow documentation / example requests should be posted to #documentation Slack channel Some suggested workflows from agenda and discussion: Parameterization of protein-ligand system using SMIRNOFF Conformer energy evaluation Minimization of multiple ligands from SDF file (is this with protein, without, both?</description></item><item><title>January 7-8, 2019 Consortium Workshop</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-07-minutes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-07-minutes/</guid><description>Minutes: Attending: All PIs and software scientists; most industry partners, postdocs, and students (including via Zoom); academic and industry community members
Visit the agenda page for more details of the workshop.</description></item><item><title>October 29, 2018 Joint Governing/Advisory Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-29-minutes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-29-minutes/</guid><description>Minutes: Attending: All PIs, both governing board members, and most advisory board members, via Zoom.
Short-term roadmap/minimum viable product: In general folks are supportive of current effort plans. However, there was consensus we need a tool for bespoke parameterization of molecules, especially internal molecules which might not be able to be disclosed to the larger effort, as part of our minimum viable product.
Funding/financials: Currently we have eight partners on board (with openforcefield.</description></item><item><title>October 11, 2018 Governing Board Meeting</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-11-minutes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-11-minutes/</guid><description>Agenda: October meeting draft agenda and start time January meeting location Maat hiring Slack Funding processing update/onboarding update Involvement with science meetings (subprojects) and project planning Discuss blog posts? Yes, just get sub-groups to do brief updates after meetings; better for keeping people up to date. Minutes: Attending: All PIs except Shirts, and both industry members, Thomas Fox and Katharina Meier
Shared the detailed budget outline Google Doc and went over the personnel who would be involved and their distribution across different locations, $ amounts, etc.</description></item><item><title>Jan 2019 Open Force Field Consortium Workshop</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/jan-2019-meeting-agenda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/jan-2019-meeting-agenda/</guid><description>We hosted the first Open Force Field Consortium Workshop in La Jolla, CA on January 7-8, 2019. The meeting was open to Consortium members and collaborators, and parts of the meeting were recorded for posting online. In addition, slides discussing current Consortium research and future plans are given below.
Details at a glance Date: January 7-8, 2018 Location: Jacobs Medical Center, UC San Diego, La Jolla, CA, Rooms 2 and 3 Local contact: Mike Gilson &amp;lt;mgilson@ucsd.</description></item><item><title>Webinar on the SMIRNOFF format and learned chemical perception Oct. 10</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/bioexcel_webinar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/bioexcel_webinar/</guid><description>Check out a webinar on the Initiative this Oct. 10 from BioExcel! MolSSI fellow Caitlin Bannan will talk about the Initiative&amp;rsquo;s overall goals and her work on learned chemical perception. Register through BioExcel, or if you can&amp;rsquo;t make it, video should be available afterwards.
Bannan&amp;rsquo;s Abstract: The Open Force Field Initiative is developing a machinery to automatically parameterize molecular mechanics force fields. An important part of this process will be automating chemical perception — the way force field parameters are assigned to a molecule based on chemical environment.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the Open Force Field Consortium</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-the-consortium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-the-consortium/</guid><description>We’re excited to announce the launch of the Open Force Field Consortium, an academic-industry collaboration designed to improve small molecule force fields used to guide pharmaceutical drug discovery. The Open Force Field Initiative is what we are calling our overall research effort, whereas the Open Force Field Consortium refers specifically to the academic-industry collaboration.
Modeling tools based on force fields assist development of therapies for diseases such as cancer and neurodegenerative disease throughout academia and industry.</description></item><item><title>Support for open source cheminformatics toolkits is coming!</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/rdkit-support-is-coming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/rdkit-support-is-coming/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work with a large-scale infrastructure overhaul of our main openforcefield toolkit following the Open Force Field Toolkit 0.1.0 prerelease, which provided an initial reference implementation of the SMIRNOFF 0.1 specification for direct chemical perception. Many thanks to all the users who provided helpful feedback in how we could improve overall usability!
While we expect the updated toolkit to be released very soon, we wanted to provide a summary of the coming changes to give you an idea of what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to:</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Open Force Field Initiative</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</guid><description>Molecular modeling is widely used in diverse pharmaceutical discovery applications, but its utility and predictive power is limited by the accuracy of the underlying molecular mechanics force field used to compute the energetics of biomolecular systems. The Open Force Field Initiative is an open effort to build iteratively more accurate force fields to improve predictive design, along with the necessary infrastructure to make these force fields easier to build and use, and to provide a modern platform for powering force field science.</description></item><item><title>Viral Families</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/viral-families/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/viral-families/</guid><description>ASAP aims to discover direct-acting antivirals with broad antiviral activity within a viral family, but the difficulty of achieving this goal means that some of our program objectives are more narrowly focused on viral family members of greatest pandemic concern.
coronaviridae Coronavirus antiviral discovery is funded by NIAID grant U19AI171399 from the National Institutes of Health.
flaviviridae Flavivirus antiviral discovery is funded by NIAID grant U19AI171399 from the National Institutes of Health.</description></item><item><title>Targeting Opportunities</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/targeting-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/targeting-opportunities/</guid><description>A targeting opportunity provides an overview of the opportunity for targeting new antivirals to a specific target protein and mode of action. This overview is intended to summarize relevant information for drug hunters, including the relevant domain and binding sites to target, notable chemical matter, rationale for antiviral effects, and other useful information in prosecuting a discovery compaign aginst the target.
Targeting Opportunity: SARS-CoV-2 / MERS-CoV Mpro protease [Targeting Opportunity] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 1 Project 5 [2023-03-19] Initial draft [2023-04-29] Major update of the targeting opportunity covering clinical background, history of outbreaks, viral biology, target biochemistry, phylogenetic analysis, etc.</description></item><item><title>Molecules</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/molecules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/molecules/</guid><description>SARS-CoV-2/MERS-CoV Mpro lead optimization assay data [metadata] [(negative) biochemical and liver microsome assay data] [SARS-CoV-2 Mpro assay protocol] [MERS-CoV Mpro assay protocol] This data release contains assay data for compounds ASAP is not pursuing toward nomination of a development candidate as part of this discovery program. Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 5 Biochemical Assay Core Data Core [2023-04-30] Initial public release of negative biochemical activity data for 182 molecules. [2023-11-07] Initial public release of negative biochemical activity data for MERS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2 Mpro and HLM/MLM data for 266 molecules.</description></item><item><title>Structures</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/structures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/structures/</guid><description>MERS-CoV/SARS-CoV-2 Mpro protease ASAP-COV-MPRO PDB group deposition of X-ray fragment screen of SARS-CoV-2 Mpro pdb-group-deposition [ 2020-04-07 ] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 2 Structural Biology Core SARS-CoV-2 main protease from Coronaviridae sp. screened against DSI poised (Enamine), Fraglites and Peplites (Newcastle university), Mini Frags (Astex), York 3D (York university), electrophile cysteine covalent (Weizman institute) fragment libraries by X-ray Crystallography at the XChem facility of Diamond Light Source beamline I04-1 Selected structures were deposited in the PDB via a group deposition.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/publications/</guid><description>ASAP aims to publish preprints to ensure our scientific advances are rapidly and openly available.</description></item><item><title>Analysis of Circulating Variants</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/circulating-variants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/circulating-variants/</guid><description>Analysis of circulating variants of SARS-CoV-2 nsp5 Mpro protease [interactive viewer] [bioRxiv preprint] Interactive viewer and dataset download of functional mutation impact scores derived from analysis of circulating SARS-CoV-2 variants Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 1 [2023-01-31] Preprint and interactive mutation viewer posted. Analysis of circulating variants of SARS-CoV-2 nsp15 endoribonuclease [interactive viewer] [bioRxiv preprint] Interactive viewer and dataset download of functional mutation impact scores derived from analysis of circulating SARS-CoV-2 variants Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 1 [2023-01-31] Preprint and interactive mutation viewer posted.</description></item><item><title>Target Product Profiles (TPPs)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/target-product-profiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/target-product-profiles/</guid><description>A Target Product Profile (TPP) describes the desired characteristics of a drug product aimed to treat a particular disease or set of diseases.
All ASAP TPPs are draft TPPs intended to help guide the development of target candidate profiles (TCPs) for antiviral discovery within the ASAP Discovery Consortium. ASAP works with stakeholders around the globe (such as the World Health Organization) to align TPPs to ensure they meet the needs of communities and fulfill our mission of global, equitable, and affordable access to antiviral therapies.</description></item><item><title>Target Enabling Packages (TEPs)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/target-enabling-packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/target-enabling-packages/</guid><description>A Target Enabling Package (TEP) is a complete data package needed to enable structure-based drug discovery against an antiviral target. Pioneered by the Structural Genomics Consortium, each TEP contains relevant protein constructs and plasmid resources for one or more viral family members, protein expression and purification protocols, crystallization conditions, structures from an X-ray fragment screen at the Diamond Light Source XChem facility, small molecule hits, and biochemical assay protocols with at least one validated inhibitor with quantifiable activity.</description></item><item><title>Assay Cascades</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/assay-cascades/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/assay-cascades/</guid><description>An assay cascade is a defined set of assays and progression criteria used by a drug discovery program to achieve its Target Candidate Profile (TCP) goals in a time- and cost-effective manner.
Assay cascade for MERS-CoV / SARS-CoV-2 oral antiviral [Asay Cascade (lead optimization)] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 5 Biochemical Assay Core Structural Biology Core Antiviral Core [2022-06-01] Initial draft Assay cascade for SARS-CoV-2 nsp3 Mac1 macrodomain oral antiviral [Assay Cascade (fragment-to-lead)] Partial SARS-CoV-2 nsp3 Mac1 macrodomain assay cascade for lead nomination Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 3 Project 5 Biochemical Assay Core Structural Biology Core Antiviral Core [2022-06-01] Initial draft EV-D68 / EV-A71 3C Protease Assay Cascade [Assay Cascade] Assay cascade for EV-D68 / EV-A71 3C Protease oral antiviral Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 3 Project 5 Biochemical Assay Core Structural Biology Core Antiviral Core [2022-07-14] Initial draft Assay cascade for SARS-CoV-2 Mpro oral antiviral [Assay Cascade (lead optimization)] Assay cascade for lead optimization campaign for SARS-CoV-2 noncovalent oral inhibitor from the COVID Moonshot [2020-03-23] Initial draft for COVID Moonshot</description></item><item><title>Assay Protocols</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/assay-protocols/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/assay-protocols/</guid><description>ASAP frequently needs to develop or scale its own biochemical assay protocols to drive discovery programs. Whenever possible, we share these protocols through protocols.io, an industry standard platform for sharing and annotating assay protocols.
MERS-CoV main protease (Mpro) activity fluorescence dose response biochemical assay [assay protocol] This is a functional, biochemical assay used to identify treatments for viral infectious disease in MERS 3C-like main viral protease. Utilizing a direct enzyme activity measurement method, the experiment was performed in a 384-well plate reading the fluorescence intensity.</description></item><item><title>Target Candidate Profiles (TCPs)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/target-candidate-profiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/target-candidate-profiles/</guid><description>A Target Candidate Profile (TCP) describes the objectives an ASAP drug discovery program aims to achieve to produce a preclinical candidate. Our TCPs are informed by the corresponding Target Product Profiles (TPPs) for the corresponding disease.
MERS-CoV / SARS-CoV-2 MPro protease oral inhibitor [Target Candidate Profile] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 5 [2023-03-01] Initial draft DENV/ZIKV NS2B/3 protease oral inhibitor draft [Target Candidate Profile] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 3 Project 5 [2023-03-01] Initial draft [2023-05-11] Consolidate DENV/ZIKV EV-D68/A71 3C protease oral inhibitor [Lead Transition Profile] [Target Candidate Profile] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 3 Project 5 [2023-06-22] Initial drafts EV-D68/A71 VP1 capsid assembly oral inhibitor [Lead Transition Profile] [Target Candidate Profile] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 3 Project 5 [2023-12-15] Initial drafts SARS-CoV-2 nsp3 Mac1 macrodomain oral inhibitor [Target Candidate Profile for lead nomination] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 3 Project 5 [2023-03-01] Initial draft SARS-CoV-2 Oral MPro protease inhibitor [Target Candidate Profile] Contributing Projects and Cores: Project 5 [2020-04-01] Initial draft</description></item><item><title>Preclinical programs</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/preclinical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/preclinical/</guid><description>SARS-CoV-2 Mpro protease See the COVID Moonshot preclinical program.</description></item><item><title>Investigational New Drug (IND) filings</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/investigational-new-drugs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/investigational-new-drugs/</guid><description>ASAP does not yet have any programs that have reached Investigational New Drug (IND) status.</description></item><item><title>Clinical trials</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/clinical-trials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/clinical-trials/</guid><description>ASAP does not currently have any programs that have reached clinical trials.</description></item><item><title>New Drug Approvals</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/new-drug-approvals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/new-drug-approvals/</guid><description>ASAP does not currently have any programs that have reached New Drug Approval (NDA) status.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/img/icons/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/outputs/img/icons/readme/</guid><description>Icons from The Noun Project Icons are CC-BY from The Noun Project
Credits (for CC-BY acknowledgments) assay-cascade.png : noun-chemistry-2954755 : Chemistry by Icon Factory from Noun Project clinical-trails.png : noun-medical-1053629 : medical by Raymond from Noun Project data.png : noun-save-5021426 : Save by Cetha Studio from Noun Project disease.png : noun-medical-3923610 : medical by Royyan Wijaya from Noun Project DMS.png : noun-mutation-4374976 : mutation by Adrien Coquet from Noun Project hit-to-lead.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/pipeline/img/icons/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/pipeline/img/icons/readme/</guid><description>Icons from The Noun Project Icons are CC-BY from The Noun Project
Credits (for CC-BY acknowledgments) assay-cascade.png : noun-chemistry-2954755 : Chemistry by Icon Factory from Noun Project clinical-trails.png : noun-medical-1053629 : medical by Raymond from Noun Project data.png : noun-save-5021426 : Save by Cetha Studio from Noun Project disease.png : noun-medical-3923610 : medical by Royyan Wijaya from Noun Project DMS.png : noun-mutation-4374976 : mutation by Adrien Coquet from Noun Project hit-to-lead.</description></item><item><title>Awards</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/rfa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/rfa/</guid><description>Applications for the ASAP AViDD Center Developmental Research Project Awards and Mentored Project Awards are currently under review with awards expected to be announced by April 2023.
Funds for these awards are provided by the National Institutes of Health under award number U19AI171399 through the NIAID Antiviral Drug Discovery (AViDD) U19 Program.
Developmental Research Project Awards Funding Opportunity Title
AI-driven Structure-enabled Antiviral Platform (ASAP) Discovery Consortium Developmental Project Award Program</description></item><item><title>Developmental and Mentored Awards</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/projects/</guid><description>Developmental Research Projects Applications for the ASAP AViDD Center Developmental Research Project Awards and Mentored Project Awards closed on 13 Jan 2023. After scoring applications by our Scientific Advisory Board, NIAID approved the following awards, which were issued on 1 May 2023.
Funds for these awards are provided by the National Institutes of Health under award number U19AI171399 through the NIAID Antiviral Drug Discovery (AViDD) U19 Program.
Defining mutational constraints of ASAP-prioritized SARS-CoV-2 target proteins via multiplexed, yeast-based cDNA Project Leader: Farren Isaacs, Yale University, New Haven, CT</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/privacy/</guid><description>ASAP Discovery Consortium Privacy Policy This Privacy Policy explains how ASAP Discovery Consortium (&amp;ldquo;we,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;us,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;) collects, uses, and safeguards your personal information when you visit our website and interact with our services. We are committed to protecting your privacy and complying with applicable data protection laws, including the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
By using the ASAP Discovery Consortium website and services, you consent to the terms outlined in this Privacy Policy.</description></item><item><title>Open Science</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/open-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/open-science/</guid><description>April 2023
Authors: Pascale Boulet, ASAP IP Strategy Consultant, Intellectual Property &amp;amp; Access Leader, DNDi
Dr Ed Griffen, ASAP Lead Optimization Project Lead, MedChemica Consultancy Ltd
Antivirals must be globally accessible to be effective against pandemics ASAP accelerates open science antiviral drug discovery to deliver oral antivirals for pandemics with the goal of global, equitable, and affordable access.
Nobody is safe unless everybody is safe. Modern air travel means infectious agents can spread easily across the globe.</description></item></channel></rss>