<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Awards on ASAP Discovery Consortium</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/</link><description>Recent content in Awards on ASAP Discovery Consortium</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awards</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/rfa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/rfa/</guid><description>Applications for the ASAP AViDD Center Developmental Research Project Awards and Mentored Project Awards are currently under review with awards expected to be announced by April 2023.
Funds for these awards are provided by the National Institutes of Health under award number U19AI171399 through the NIAID Antiviral Drug Discovery (AViDD) U19 Program.
Developmental Research Project Awards Funding Opportunity Title
AI-driven Structure-enabled Antiviral Platform (ASAP) Discovery Consortium Developmental Project Award Program</description></item><item><title>Developmental and Mentored Awards</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/awards/projects/</guid><description>Developmental Research Projects Applications for the ASAP AViDD Center Developmental Research Project Awards and Mentored Project Awards closed on 13 Jan 2023. After scoring applications by our Scientific Advisory Board, NIAID approved the following awards, which were issued on 1 May 2023.
Funds for these awards are provided by the National Institutes of Health under award number U19AI171399 through the NIAID Antiviral Drug Discovery (AViDD) U19 Program.
Defining mutational constraints of ASAP-prioritized SARS-CoV-2 target proteins via multiplexed, yeast-based cDNA Project Leader: Farren Isaacs, Yale University, New Haven, CT</description></item></channel></rss>