<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Force Field Initiative on ASAP Discovery Consortium</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/tags/open-force-field-initiative/</link><description>Recent content in Open Force Field Initiative on ASAP Discovery Consortium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asapdiscovery.org/tags/open-force-field-initiative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Webinar by Chaya Stern: Fragmenting molecules for QC torsion drives (Jun 4, 2019)</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-torsions-chaya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/webinar-torsions-chaya/</guid><description>You can watch this webinar on YouTube and access slides on Zenodo.
Chaya Stern (Chodera lab) will give a webinar on Jun 4 at 11 am (EDT) under title “Fragmenting molecules for QC torsion drives”, based on her talk presented at the ACS Orlando conference (Mar 31 - Apr 4, 2019). Join the webinar in real time via Zoom link (https://meetmsk.zoom.us/j/987691623) or for those who can’t make it, Chaya’s talk will be recorded and shared on the website.</description></item><item><title>Open Force Field Initiative applies for NIH funding</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/seeking-nih-funding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/seeking-nih-funding/</guid><description>The ultimate goal of the Open Force Field Initiative is to produce modern, high-quality tools for building better force fields, and to apply these tools to produce consistently more accurate generations of biomolecular force fields that are incredibly easy to use in a variety of molecular simulation packages.
Anyone who has tried simulating complex, heterogeneous systems involving small molecules, proteins, lipids, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, post-translational modifications, cofactors, and covalent ligands (or any subset of these!</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Open Force Field Initiative</title><link>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asapdiscovery.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</guid><description>Molecular modeling is widely used in diverse pharmaceutical discovery applications, but its utility and predictive power is limited by the accuracy of the underlying molecular mechanics force field used to compute the energetics of biomolecular systems. The Open Force Field Initiative is an open effort to build iteratively more accurate force fields to improve predictive design, along with the necessary infrastructure to make these force fields easier to build and use, and to provide a modern platform for powering force field science.</description></item></channel></rss>